Guide to the Sheila Lukins Papers 1945-2009 (Bulk 1980-2000) MSS 281
© 2010 Fales Library and Special Collections
Sheila Lukins Papers
Bulk, 1980-2000
1945-2009 (Bulk 1980-2000)
MSS 281
© 2010 Fales Library and Special Collections
37.61 linear feet
Sheila Lukins (1942- 2009) was a food writer, cookbook author, grocery-store owner, and caterer. She was a co-author of The Silver Palate Cookbook, and later became the food editor of Parade magazine, succeeding Julia Child in the position and contributing to her column there, "Simply Delicious." The Sheila Lukins Papers include drafts of recipes for Parade magazine; notebooks containing writing on foods from the United States and around the world; correspondence; publicity and press clippings for Lukins, her store, and her cookbooks; issues of Parade magazine and other magazines; CD-ROMs; and videocassettes.
Lukins, Sheila
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Biographical Note
Sheila Lukins (1942- 2009) was a food writer, cookbook author, grocer, and caterer. Born in Philadelphia, PA, and raised in Norwalk and Westport, CT, Lukins attended Tyler School of Fine Arts and the School of Visual Arts, and received a bachelor's in Art Education from the New York University in 1970. After graduating, Lukins moved to London with her husband, Richard Lukins, where she attended Le Cordon Bleu. On returning to New York in 1972, Lukins began the Other Woman Catering Company out of her apartment at the Dakota, at Central Park West and 72nd Street. In 1977, she opened the Silver Palate gourmet grocery with partner Julee Russo on the Upper West Side.
With Russo, Lukins coauthored The Silver Palate Cookbook, in 1982, which has since sold more than two and a half million copies. Lukins went on to author other bestselling cookbooks, such as The Silver Palate Cookbook, The Silver Palate Good Times Cookbook, U.S.A. Cookbook, The New Basics Cookbook, Celebrate! and All Around the World Cookbook.
In 1986, Lukins became the food editor of Parade magazine, succeeding Julia Childs in the position, and contributing to her column there, "Simply Delicious".
In 1988, The Silver Palate was sold to investors and eventually closed, in 1993. Lukins won many awards as a small-business owner and a cookbook author and was a member of Les Dames d'Escoffier, the American Institute of Wine and Food, the James Beard Foundation, and the International Association of Cooking Professionals.
References
Moskin, J. (2009, August 30). "Sheila Lukins, 66, Dies; Awakened Taste Buds." The New York Times. Retrieved from http://www.nytimes.com/2009/08/31/dining/31lukins.html.
Parade. (2009, August 30). "Sheila Lukins, PARADE’s Beloved Food Columnist, Dies at 66." Retrieved from http://www.parade.com/news/2009/08/sheila-lukins.html.
Nelson, V. J. (2009, September 1). "Sheila Lukins dies at 66; co-author of 'The Silver Palate' cookbook." Los Angeles Times. Retrieved from http://www.latimes.com/news/obituaries/la-me-sheila-lukins1-2009sep01,0,1812170.story.
Star Chefs. (2000). "Sheila Lukins." http://www.starchefs.com/SLuins/html/bio_s_lukins.shtml.
Arrangement
Material, when dated, is arranged chronologically. All undated material is arranged alphabetically by folder label in order to facillitate ease of access.
Scope and Content
The Sheila Lukins Papers includes drafts of recipes for Parade magazine; notebooks containing writing on foods from the United States and around the world; correspondence; publicity and press clippings for Lukins, her store, and her cookbooks; issues of Parade magazine and other magazines (some of which include work by or about Lukins); cookbook CD-ROMs by Lukins; and videocassettes featuring Lukins's television appearances.
The collection is arranged into five series:
Series I: Professional Files
Series II: Photographic Materials
Series III: Media
Series IV: Periodicals and Clippings
Series V: Objects
Separated Materials
The following books were removed and cataloged as part of the Fales Food Studies Book Collection. They can be located by searching "Sheila Lukins" in BobCat, the NYU catalog.
Gale, Bill. (1970). A Gentleman's Guide to Memorable Hospitality.
Fast, Barry. (1984). The Catfish Cookbook.
Gifts from the Christmas Kitchen. c. 1
Gifts from the Christmas Kitchen. c. 2
The Silver Palate Pantry Recipes.
Related Archival Materials note
Les Dames d'Escoffier New York Archive, MSS 150
Color prints (photographs).; Cookbooks.; Cooking |v Periodicals; Cooking, American |x History |y 20th Century; Food industry and trade |z New York (State) |z New York; Food |v Periodicals.; Gourmet food industry.; Grocery trade.; Recipes.; Videocassettes.; Women in the food industry
- Series I: Professional Files, 1976-2007
  Scope and Content
  Series comprises material relating to Sheila Lukins role as food writer, cookbook author, and proprietor of the Silver Palate. Materials include correspondence; recipes; drafts for food columns at Parade; correspondence, publicity, and other materials related to her cookbooks; press and clippings for Lukins, her cookbooks, or the Silver Palate.
  Arrangement
  Subseries A, C, D, E, and G are arranged chronologically. Undated material is filed at the end of the series in alphabetical order by folder label.
  Subseries B and F are arranged alphabetically by folder label.
  - Subseries A: Parade Files, 1991-2007
    Subseries comprises correspondence, drafts of menus and recipes, letters and recipes from readers, and other material related to Lukins's Parade magazine column "Simply Delicious."
    Subseries is arranged chronologically. Undated material is filed at the end of the series in alphabetical order by folder label.
    - Parade/Jan/Feb,March, November 11, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - July/August Parade, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sept/October/Nov/Dec 92, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Parade 1993 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Parade 1993 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Parade 1994 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Parade 1994 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Parade 1996 1 of 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Parade 1996 2 of 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Parade 1996 3 of 5 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Parade 1996 4 of 5 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Parade 1996 5 of 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Parade Recipes, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Parade Recipes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Parade Recipes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Parade Recipes, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Parade Recipes, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Parade Recipes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Parade Recipes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Parade Recipes, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Parade Recipes, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Parade Cookie Recipe Contest, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Parade 2002 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Parade 2002 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Parade Recipes, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Delores J. Sterling Parade Correspondence, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Parade Recipes, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Parade Recipes, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Parade Recipes, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Parade Notes 2006 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Parade 2007 1 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Parade 2007 2 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Parade 2007 3 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Parade Recipes, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Parade Recipes, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Amusing Letters, Parade, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - April, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - April/May/June Parade, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - August, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - December, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - February, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - January, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - July, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - June, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Letters from Readers, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - March, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - May, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Misc. Info, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - November, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Parade Recipe Indexes 1 of 3, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Parade Recipe Indexes 2 of 3, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Parade Recipe Indexes 3 of 3, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Parade Permission Forms, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Recipes from Readers 1 of 3, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Recipes from Readers 2 of 3, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Recipes from Readers 3 of 3, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Pending Reader Mail 1 of 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Pending Reader Mail 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - September 1 of 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - September 2 of 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Thanksgiving 1 of 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Thanksgiving 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Tips Columns in Parade 1 of 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Tips Columns in Parade 2 of 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Subseries B: Notebooks, undated
    Subseries comprises notebooks kept by Lukins documenting food, ingredients, and recipes from her travels across the United States and abroad.
    Subseries is arranged alphabetically by folder label.
    - Caribbean Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cuba Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - England/Ireland Notebooks, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Greece/Turkey Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - India Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Mexico Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - [Notebooks from Various U.S. Cities], undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Party Planner, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Portugal/N. Africa Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Recipe Notebooks, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Research Notebooks, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Russian Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Scandinavia Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - South America Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Spring of '97 Notebook, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - State Research Notecards, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Untitles Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Vermont, San Antonio, Santa Fe Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Subseries C: The Silver Palatte, 1981-1992
    Subseries comprises correspondence, publicity, press, and other material related to Sheila Lukins and Julee Russo's cookbook The Silver Palate Cookbook. Subseries also includes some material related to Lukins and Russo's gourmet grocery store, the Silver Palate.
    - "The Silver Palate News" and "The Silver Palate Catalogue", 1981-1983, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - The Silver Palate Hors d'Oeuvres Calendars, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Silver Palatte Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Silver Palate 10th Anniversary, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Silver Palate 10th Anniversary Pamphlets, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - [Loose Documents], undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Silver Palate 25th Anniversary, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Silver Palate 25th Anniversary, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - The Silver Palate Cookbook (Annotated), undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - The Silver Palate Cookbook Articles, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Silver Palate Cookbook Information, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Silver Palate Corporate Profiles, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - The Silver Palate, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Silver Palate Promotional Material, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Silver Palate Publications, Photograph, and Sticker, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Silver Palate Cookbook Publicity Highlights 1 of 3, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Silver Palate Cookbook Publicity Highlights 2 of 3, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Silver Palate Cookbook Publicity Highlights 3 of 3 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Subseries D: Cookbook Files, 1976-2003
    Subseries comprises research notes, outlines, correspondence, promotional material and publicity, and other material related to Lukins's other cookbooks. Subseries mostly covers material from the cookbooks U.S.A. Cookbook and All Around the World.
    - Cookbook Permissions, Michy's Menu, The Catered Affair Resolution, 1976, 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Book Party USA, May 6, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - All Around the U.S.A., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - All Around the World, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - A Whole New Palate, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - U.S.A. Cookbook Publicity, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - USA Cookbook Research 1 of 7, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - USA Cookbook Research 2 of 7, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - USA Cookbook Research 3 of 7, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - USA Cookbook Research 4 of 7, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - USA Cookbook Research 5 of 7, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - USA Cookbook Research 6 of 7, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - USA Cookbook Research 7 of 7, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous Menus and Recipes, 1997-2003
    Subseries comprises catering menus and recipes assembled by Lukins for various entities besides Parade, the Silver Palate, or her cookbooks.
    - Degustibus, September 18, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Silo + Daily [Needs], November 1, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - United Meals, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - UAC Contract, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - United Holiday Meals, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Catfish 1 of 2, May 1999 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Catfish 2 of 2, May 1999 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - United Hol. Meals Xmas 1 of 3, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - United Hol. Meals Xmas 2 of 3, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - United Hol. Meals Xmas 3 of 3, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - United Poultry Meals, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - United Meals, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Johnson & Wales Dinner, February 20, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - De Gustibus, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - "May 1st Celebrations Cocktails", 2003 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - "Recipes", undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Breakfast, Plated Dinners I, II, III Lunch, II, III; Breakfast & Brunch Buffets 1 of 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Breakfast, Plated Dinners I, II, III Lunch, II, III; Breakfast & Brunch Buffets 2 of 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Ham, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Bake Sale, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Con Agra Project, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Lamb Council 1 of 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Lamb Council 2 of 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Perdue Projects, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Recipes, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sheila Lukins Publicity Highlights ( Ten by Sheila), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - United Airlines Economy Class Meals, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - United Airlines Menus 1 of 3, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - United Airlines Menus 2 of 3, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - United Airlines Menus 3 of 3, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Vertical File: Appetizers-Soups (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Vertical File: Bread + Rolls, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Vertical File: Fish, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Vertical File: Desserts, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Vertical File: Eggs - Cheese - Pasta, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Vertical File: Meats - Poultry, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Vertical File: Vegetables, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Vertical File: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Subseries F: Press, undated
    Subseries comprises press and clippings about Lukins, her grocery store, or her cookbooks.
    - Clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Loose Newspaper Clippings 1 of 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Loose Newspaper Clippings 2 of 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Loose Newspaper Clippings 3 of 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Loose Newspaper Clippings 4 of 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Misc. Clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Publicity and Articles, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Publicity and Articles, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Publicity and Articles, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Publicity and Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Sheila Lukins Clips (Sheila's Copies) 1 of 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Sheila Lukins Clips (Sheila's Copies) 2 of 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Sheila Lukins Publicity Highlights, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Ten by Sheila, The East Hampton Star, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Various Clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Subseries G: Miscellaneous Professional Files, 1991-2007
    Subseries comprises material that could not be integrated into the main subseries but still reflects some aspect of Lukins's professional life, including material related to Lukins's travel and research on international cuisine, her involvement with Les Dames d'Escoffier, her student records and work on art education, an NYU Distinguished Alumni Achievement Award she received, and her early catering work.
    That said, there is some material in this subseries that could easily fit into one or more of the other, more specific subseries above; however, the archivist thought it best to leave this material, in the order in which he received them.
    - Travel Asia, April 1991 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Build a Better Burger Contest, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Draeger's Cooking School Class Catalog, May-August 2007 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Book Party, May 17 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Awards, Biography, and Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Catering Information 1 of 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Catering Information 2 of 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - "The Cheeses of Picholine", undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Food Television Network, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Georgia Map; Louisiana Map, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - I and Albert Souvenir Brochure, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Loose Binder Documents 1 of 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Loose Binder Documents 2 of 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Loose Binder Documents 3 of 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Loose Binder Documents 4 of 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Loose Documents 1 of 8, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Loose Documents 2 of 8, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Loose Documents 3 of 8, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Loose Documents 4 of 8, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Loose Documents 5 of 8, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Loose Documents 6 of 8, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Loose Documents 7 of 8, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Loose Documents 8 of 8, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "Menu", undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - New York University, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - The Other Woman Catering Receipts, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Photographs and Letters, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Russia 1 of 2, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Russia 2 of 2, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - School 1 of 2, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - School 2 of 2, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Thai Cooking School and Thai Culture Programme, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Series II: Photographic Materials, undated
  Series comprises photographs taken of and by Sheila Lukins. Most photographs concern travel across the United States and abroad for food-related events and research (though the photographs appear to be a mix of personal vacation photos and photographs of food, food vendors, and food-related events). A few photographs are publicity shots for the Silver Palate grocery and The Silver Palate Cookbook.
  Eight photograph binders that were originally labeled #1 through #8 appear in numerical order. Unnumbered binders are ordered alphabetically, with unlabeled binders at the end. Photographic sleeves that were too large for binders are placed in folders corresponding to their binder and ordered alphabetically by their original binder's label.
  - Photographic Materials (Binders)
    - #1 LA Times Book Tour Signings Chicago Boston Seattle Portland Denver Dallas Houston Chevy Chase Annapolis Goshen Festival, undated (Photo-album Binder A)
    - #2 Bridgewater Co. Fair, CT. Minneapolis/St. Paul, MN Shaker Dinner, Hancock, MA Savannah/Charleston Lima Bean Festival Cranberry Boggs, undated (Photo-album Binder B)
    - #3 Amish/Lancaster NY Area Diners Maytag Blue Cheese Gospel Brunch, Stanford, CT Williamsburg Catfish Fest Belzoni, MS Coach Farms Vermont Minn. Wild Rice NYC Farmers Market, undated (Photo-album Binder C)
    - #4 Gilroy Garlic Festival Sonoma Co. Fair Sonoma Valley Nantucket, undated (Photo-album Binder D)
    - #5 Shad Planking - Wakefield, VA Smithfield Ham Santa Fe San Antonio Mushroom Hunt - Boyne City, MI, undated (Photo-album Binder E)
    - #6 Cheese Festival, Wisconson Door County, Fish Boil Peach Festival, Ft. Valley, GA Seattle, undated (Photo-album Binder F)
    - #7 Clam Festival, Yarmouth, MN Cabbage Island Lobster Bake Petosky Sour Cherries South Dakota Church Supper - Virginia Kansas City Laura Chenel New Orleans Castroville, Carmel, undated (Photo-album Binder G)
    - #8 New Orleans, LA Hawaii Hunger Hotline Dinner Alaska, undated (Photo-album Binder H)
    - Argentia, Brazil, undated (Photo-album Binder I)
    - Chile, Cuba, Denmark, Finland, Greece, undated (Photo-album Binder J)
    - India, undated (Photo-album Binder K)
    - Indonesia, undated (Photo-album Binder L)
    - Jamaica, Martinique, Mexico, undated (Photo-album Binder M)
    - Morrocco, Portugal, undated (Photo-album Binder N)
    - Russia [2], undated (Photo-album Binder O)
    - Scotland and Ireland, undated (Photo-album Binder P)
    - Spain, Sweden, Turkey, undated (Photo-album Binder Q)
    - Tunisia, undated (Photo-album Binder R)
    - [Unlabeled Binder], undated (Photo-album Binder S)
    - [Unlabeled Binder], undated (Photo-album Binder T)
    - [Unlabeled Binder], undated (Photo-album Binder U)
  - Photographic Materials (Folders)
    - England, Ireland 1 of 3, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - England, Ireland 2 of 3, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - England, Ireland 3 of 3, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - India 1 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - India 2 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Jamaica, Martinique, Cuba 1 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Jamaica, Martinique, Cuba 2 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Mexico 1 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Mexico 2 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Russia [1] 1 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Russia [1] 2 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Scandinavia 1 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Scandinavia 2 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - South America 1 of 4, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - South America 2 of 4, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - South America 3 of 4, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - South America 4 of 4, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Tunisia, Morocco, Spain, Portugal 1 of 3, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Tunisia, Morocco, Spain, Portugal 2 of 3, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Tunisia, Morocco, Spain, Portugal 3 of 3, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Turkey, Greece 1 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Turkey, Greece 2 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Loose Photographs, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Series III: Media, 1983-1999
  Series comprises CD-ROMs and videotapes from the collection.
  Subseries A and B are arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Use
    Access copies may not be available. Inquire with Fales archivist.
  - Subseries B: Published Media, 1985-1997
    Subseries comprises CD-ROM versions of Lukins's cookbooks and two copies of the videocassette The Silver Palate Good Times Live
    Subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Dinner at Eight Computer Disk, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      General note
      Format: Floppy disks
    - The Silver Palate Collection Computer Disk, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 19)